<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technology on The Tarkus Factory</title>
    <link>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technology on The Tarkus Factory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sway: The brief introduction to tiling window managers</title>
      <link>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/2024_02_14_swaywm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/2024_02_14_swaywm/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t lie to you that I&amp;rsquo;ve had some free time these days, which I&amp;rsquo;ve taken advantage of to learn about GNU/Linux Desktop. By installing it on two laptops, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to learn about the kernel and the Ubuntu and Fedora operating systems. However, when I began my journey, I was playing in a safe environment like GNOME, this window manager that provides almost all the tools you need to start without having to tinker too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding comfort in the GNU/Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/2024_01_16_linux_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/2024_01_16_linux_experience/</guid>
      <description>I have been a Windows user for most of my life, and for a little over two years, I have used MacOS; this article talks about my reasons and experiences in using GNU/Linux as an operating system, the transition, its strengths, and weaknesses.
My first motivation is a mixture of curiosity and the desire to find a free operating system, with the same idea in mind in my previous post where I wanted to move more towards free software, the main piece was the operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>set up NeoVim &#43; Tmux for a Data Science Workflow with Julia</title>
      <link>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/004_nvim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://smigle-hugo-theme.netlify.app/posts/004_nvim/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will provide some notes on getting started with Neovim for a Data Science Workflow. This setup is not strictly related to Julia and can also be used with Python and R. The idea is to work with a double panel structure, where one side contains your code and the other side has the REPL, which receives the snippets of code you send from the code side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
