<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Tarkus Factory</title>
    <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Tarkus Factory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://indymnv.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sway: The brief introduction to tiling window managers</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/2024_02_14_swaywm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/2024_02_14_swaywm/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t lie to you that I&amp;rsquo;ve had some free time these days, which I&amp;rsquo;ve taken advantage of to learn about GNU/Linux Desktop. By installing it on two laptops, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to learn about the kernel and the Ubuntu and Fedora operating systems. However, when I began my journey, I was playing in a safe environment like GNOME, this window manager that provides almost all the tools you need to start without having to tinker too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding comfort in the GNU/Linux Desktop</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/2024_01_16_linux_experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/2024_01_16_linux_experience/</guid>
      <description>I have been a Windows user for most of my life, and for a little over two years, I have used MacOS; this article talks about my reasons and experiences in using GNU/Linux as an operating system, the transition, its strengths, and weaknesses.
My first motivation is a mixture of curiosity and the desire to find a free operating system, with the same idea in mind in my previous post where I wanted to move more towards free software, the main piece was the operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Mastodon to Free software: My little experience</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/008_free_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/008_free_software/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It has been a while since I decided to purge several of my social networks (including Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn) and mainly stick to Mastodon as the only platform for interacting with people on the internet whom I don&amp;rsquo;t really know. So far, it has been a positive experience, and I have no doubts that it has improved my quality of life. Furthermore, it has opened up a world that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t very aware of and that I have become increasingly interested in: The world of Free software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating your own blog with Julia and Franklin</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/006_build_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/006_build_blog/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we are going to discuss how to build your own blog with Julia and Franklin.jl, a popular static site generator among Julia users who create their own blogs or even build websites for tutorials. I hope that if you are reading this entry and you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own space, it can motivate you to build your own website.
Some Reasons to Create Your Own Blog Blogs may sound old-fashioned, something created by people who are still living in the 90s, typing with passion about the political system while listening to Soundgarden in the background and drinking some kind of cheap beer&amp;hellip; or programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>set up NeoVim &#43; Tmux for a Data Science Workflow with Julia</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/004_nvim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/004_nvim/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will provide some notes on getting started with Neovim for a Data Science Workflow. This setup is not strictly related to Julia and can also be used with Python and R. The idea is to work with a double panel structure, where one side contains your code and the other side has the REPL, which receives the snippets of code you send from the code side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using evotrees.jl for time series prediction</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/003_publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/003_publish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this post, I want to show an analysis of a time series that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Usually, when dealing with time series, it is not so common to use machine learning algorithms (without at least trying more traditional models like the ARIMA family), but I still wanted to test how well a GBM model fits for these kinds of problems that are so popular.
NOTE: I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend starting with models of this type for time series problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to scrape data with Python using selenium and Pandas</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/002_publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/002_publish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this tutorial, I will dedicate myself to explaining how web scraping can be done from a platform where a dynamic interaction of the web application is required, this is quite useful when obtaining data from different links within the platform and where it is necessary a management scheme of the front-end components to carry it out.
Here there are mainly two essential libraries, the first is selenium which corresponds to a framework that operates for multiple languages and serves to automate and control the browser, while Pandas for data manipulation will allow us to read data tables directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Happiness Report - EDA &amp; clustering with Julia</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/005_happines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/005_happines/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this post is to show Julia as a language for data analysis and Machine Learning. Sadly Kaggle does not support Julia Kernels (hopefully, they will add it in the future). Therefore I wanted to take advantage of this space to show a reimplementation of Python/R Notebooks to Julia. In this context, I took data on happiness in countries in 2021 and some factors considered in this exciting survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why have I decided to open a blog?</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/001_publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/001_publish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The purpose of starting this blog is to create a space where I can write about topics that interest me related to technology, the world of quantitative methods for decision making, programming, among others.
But why create a blog, if there are so many spaces out there that are more convenient than building one? The truth is, I wanted to have a more independent space and not too comfortable on third parties (nor benefit them), although there are spaces like Twitter (which seems to be in greater decline every day) or Medium, I simply thought that the best thing I could do is to have a personal space, and given that the dream of owning a house seems to be increasingly distant for my generation, well at least I can settle for having a blog, right?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
