<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on The Tarkus Factory</title>
    <link>https://indymnv.dev/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on The Tarkus Factory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://indymnv.dev/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>set up NeoVim &#43; Tmux for a Data Science Workflow with Julia</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/004_nvim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/004_nvim/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will provide some notes on getting started with Neovim for a Data Science Workflow. This setup is not strictly related to Julia and can also be used with Python and R. The idea is to work with a double panel structure, where one side contains your code and the other side has the REPL, which receives the snippets of code you send from the code side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to scrape data with Python using selenium and Pandas</title>
      <link>https://indymnv.dev/posts/002_publish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://indymnv.dev/posts/002_publish/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this tutorial, I will dedicate myself to explaining how web scraping can be done from a platform where a dynamic interaction of the web application is required, this is quite useful when obtaining data from different links within the platform and where it is necessary a management scheme of the front-end components to carry it out.
Here there are mainly two essential libraries, the first is selenium which corresponds to a framework that operates for multiple languages and serves to automate and control the browser, while Pandas for data manipulation will allow us to read data tables directly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
